# **MELVIN RIVERA**

# **UX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER**



Senior designer/developer with 25+ experience in product/marketing design and app development. Clients include: Apple, Universal, Sony, FOX, Paramount, Adobe and MGM. Passionate about creating delightful user experiences and supporting the latest iOS platform features. Today, I'm a Senior UX product designer at NBC Universal.

# **INFO**

#### **Email**

melvitax@me.com

#### **Phone**

+1 646 620-6068

#### **Portfolio**

www.melvitax.com

# **SKILLS**

#### iOS, tvOS Development

SwiftUI, Swift, Objective-C, Git

## **Web Development**

HTML, JS, CSS, PHP, NodeJS

## **UX Design**

Motion graphics & interaction, rapid prototyping, data driven design, wire-framing, user flows, style guides, a/b testing

# **EDUCATION**

## Otis College of Art and Design

Los Angeles, CA — Graphic Design Aug 1992 - Jan 1995

# REFERENCES

**Lori Hill**, Software Engineering Manager - Peacock +1 (425) 681-1858

**Shezad Morani**, Senior Dir, Product & UX Design - NBCNews Digital +1 (206) 799-9991

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior UX Designer - NBC Universal**

Oct 2013 - Present

Working on the next generation of news apps. Leading product design sprints, discovery sessions, quick prototyping and contributing to the code base in Swift and Swift UI. Highlights: Won Best Mobile Innovation, Best Mobile App, Best Overall Design and Redesign industry Awards.

#### Designer/Developer/Founder - All Forces

2009 - Present

Developing my own apps from concept to final execution, releasing them under the All Forces label and creating all marketing material for it. Highlights: Featured in "Tapworthy: Designing Great iPhone Apps" book and the original iPad TV commercial from Apple.

## **Freelance Work**

1995 - Present

Offering design and programming services to clients for apps, websites, movie posters, corporate identity etc. Clients: Associated Press, Apple, Warner Bros., MGM, Buster Ink., Lifetime, CNN.

#### **Art Director, Mammoth Advertising**

Sep 2006 - Jun 2009

Worked on websites for film, TV and Broadway. Created corporate identities and campaigns. Interacted with clients and worked on pitching ideas. Clients: MGM, Weinstein, IFC, Paramount, FOX, Your Tango and Lions Gate Films.

#### Creative Director, Co-founder, Mostasa Design Jan 2000 - Jan 2003

Founded a small entertainment design company. Responsible for leading a creative team, managing client relationships and writing proposals. Clients: MGM, FOX, Warner Bros., Sony, MTV and Adobe. Highlights: Won several industry design awards; featured on HOW magazine and Design Interact; featured on the Adobe and Apple websites; speaker at WWDC and Internet World Conference; worked on three James Bond film marketing campaigns.

#### Art Director, MGM

Jan 1997 - Jan 2000

Worked designing movie posters, billboards, bus wraps, magazine and newspaper ads. Designed and programmed websites for MGM's theatrical film releases. This included writing proposals, doing photo shoots and interacting with vendors.

#### **Art Director, Dawn Patrol**

Jan 1995 - Jan 1997

Designed promotional material for films including posters, billboards, ads, DVD and game packaging. Clients: Columbia/Tristar, MGM, Sony and FOX.